[music]
>> Hi everyone and welcome to this Business
Central launch edition session on Cloud
for Sovereignty. My name is Joost. I'm
the product owner for some of the
functionality that makes up Cloud for
Sovereignty that will be presenting
today. And I'm joined today by my
colleague
Hey, I'm Christina. I'm responsible for
release management and compliance in
Business Central.
And today we're going to talk about some
of the things that you can do on your
side and what Microsoft does for
protecting your data.
First, I want to make sure that we are
all aligned on the terminology on
sovereign clouds. So, we have the Cloud
for Sovereignty which is about
controlling and securing your data in
the public cloud. And then we have on
the other hand the sovereign private
cloud and the national partner clouds.
And I think it's important to understand
where Business Central is. We are of
course in the public cloud.
Today, the agenda is going to be me
talking about the European digital
commitments that we have in Microsoft.
And then we're going to drill into some
of the capabilities and functionalities
that are already available for you in
Business Central and how to set up the
protection of your data.
Before we get into the technical part, I
want to anchor Microsoft's five digital
commitments
which handles expand the AI and cloud
ecosystem across Europe and how we
uphold digital resilience even in crisis
and how we make sure to protect European
data and defend the cybersecurity
threats for in Europe.
These commitments are not just
commitments. It's also how we drive all
our work and engineering capabilities
and compliance in Microsoft and
especially for Business Central.
So, let's start looking into these five
commitments.
The first commitment is about scale and
choices in Europe cloud footprints. Last
year in Europe, Microsoft uh shared a
commitment that we want to increase our
capacity on data centers with 40% across
16 uh countries in Europe. We also
engaging with third-party actors um such
as Capgemini in and Orange and also in
Germany with SAP and Atos systems.
This intent is uh so to combine
Microsoft technologies and local
ownership, governance, and operational
control and ensuring that Europe has
capacity choices and
um a local participation.
Capacity is one thing, but resilience is
about what happens under pressure.
That's where the second commitment comes
in. This commitment focuses on
operational and legal resilience in
Europe. Microsoft will provide cloud
services through entities in Europe and
those will be operating under European
laws.
Microsoft has also established a digital
resilience commitment in all countries
with um governments and European
Commission, which means that this is a
legal binding
part of the contracts that Microsoft uh
goes into securing uh continuity of
cloud services even
during geopolitical
volatility.
And we want to emphasize also that
Microsoft has uh also stipulated that
they will go to court if there is any
um disputes on these matters.
Resilience and trust also depend on
where the data lives
and how it's handled. The next
commitment
is about the EU data boundary project
that Microsoft has been working on for
some quite some time and we completed
last year. This means that there are
multiple options for securing and
encrypting your data and keep it it safe
in Europe.
A notable point is that Microsoft has
made a promise to compensate customers
if their data is disclosed within a
violation of EU law.
Privacy and security go a hand in hand
and we also make sure that have a fourth
commitment
on how to handle cybersecurity in
Europe.
We have a strong track record of helping
defend critical data and technology.
Cybersecurity in Europe is important for
us and Microsoft has established a
council
which are driving a some of the
cybersecurity regulations such as Zora,
NIS 2, and CRA.
It's important to emphasize that
security and trust is key factors for
Microsoft and is embedded in all the
work we do across the whole
organization.
Finally, once you have capacity,
resilience, privacy, and security, the
fifth commitment is about growth.
We want to make sure that we boost
economic competitiveness in Europe
and give access to data centers, AI
skill training, public previews, and on
board on partnerships.
We have a strong open source model in AI
development
and we make sure that if you choose to
transfer to another cloud provider, it
can happen smooth and without any fee.
It is important for Microsoft that
European startups can take advantage of
the knowledge and the technology that
Microsoft has.
This was some details on Microsoft's
five digital commitments. Um this is
also available in our documentation
where you can read more about this in
details.
Let's go into more details on how you
can protect yourself in Business
Central. Over to you, Joost. Yes, thank
you, Christina. So, the Cloud for
Sovereignty makes up four separate
functional areas
that help customers protect their
environments and their their data.
Um, the first area I will cover today is
uh, access controls. So, access controls
are about enforcing layered access to
meet uh, a customer's sovereignty and
privacy needs.
Uh, for Business Central, this makes up
three separate categories. First,
there's the role-based access control
to manage uh, who can access an
environment and what level of access
should they get once they're in that
environment.
Next, there's the privileged identity
management, which allows customers to
grant uh, elevated access on a temporary
and reviewed basis.
Finally, for partners accessing
customers' environments,
there's the granular delegated admin
permissions, otherwise known as GDAP,
um, that customers can use to grant
partners access to those environments
and give them the right level of access.
Firstly, there's the role-based access
control in Dynamics Business Central.
So, this determines um, what access
regular users entering Business Central
environments have and what they can do
within those environments.
Um, the first level at which role-based
access control is set is at the
environment level. So, customers can use
security groups to uh, grant or restrict
users access to individual environments
within a tenant.
Uh, so it's possible to say this subset
of users should only have access to this
particular environment.
Next, there's users and groups in Entra
ID um, to manage the level
of uh, entitlement that users should get
within an environment.
So, um, for example, you could have a
finance users group in your Microsoft
Entra
and this group gives uh, users that work
within the finance department access
they need within Business Central uh, to
manage those finances.
Um what's important to call here out
here is that if you have groups that
grant elevated permissions within
Business Central, you can use privileged
identity management to make sure that
this access is temporary and uh
reviewed.
The next level of R back in Business
Central is entitlements. So, of course,
a user needs a license to uh
authenticate to Business Central.
And that license determines what modules
in Business Central are available to
that user. So, for example, a user with
Essentials license cannot use uh
functionality that's only included with
a Premium license.
And then finally, at the the finest
grain of group access
uh is the permission set. So, you can uh
define permission sets in Business
Central and assign those to an Entra
group to make sure that users only get
the uh permissions inside an environment
that they need to complete their tasks.
Next, there's privileged identity
management for Dynamics 365 Business
Central.
This uh functionality from Entra lets
Business Central customers temporarily
uh grant customers or users within a
customer tenant access to, for example,
an Entra role or security group.
Um so, for example, when it comes to
assigning an Entra role, um you can make
sure that that users that need to access
the admin center with the Dynamics 365
Business Central administrator role
only can do so temporarily and once
approved by uh someone who reviews
these uh role assignments.
Secondly, you can also control security
group memberships, so that's uh for
example, groups that grant access to an
environment
or groups that grant uh elevated
permissions within an environment
um are bound to groups that users only
have temporary access to whenever they
need that level of access.
And then finally, um there's the
conditional access functionality in
Entra, and this allows customers to set
conditions to sign in to Business
Central.
So, for example, a customer can
determine that a user should only be
allowed to sign in from a particular IP
address or only if they've authenticated
using 2FA.
To create a conditional access policy
for your Business Central environments,
you go into Entra, create a new
conditional access policy, and make sure
you select Dynamics 365 Business Central
as target resource for your access
policy.
Finally,
um most of our customers work with
partners to administer and manage their
environments.
And the system we use for partners to
access customer tenants and environments
is called granular delegated admin
permissions,
otherwise known as GDAP.
Um this lets customers approve any um
Entra role assignments that partners
need to access customer environments. Uh
for Business Central, we recommend using
the Dynamics 365 Business Central
administrator role
as the least privileged role that allows
for access to Business Central
environments in a tenant.
The next functional area for cloud for
sovereignty is security controls. This
is the uh measures we implement on our
end to make sure that customer data
stays secure and isolated.
So, firstly, it's important to note that
every Business Central environment is
its own dedicated isolated SQL database.
So, there's no commingling of data, and
these environments are completely
isolated from each other.
Uh of course, these environments are
encrypted. Um so, by default, they're
encrypted at rest by key um that
Microsoft owns,
but customers can choose to use their
own key. Uh this is called
customer-managed encryption key.
Um
using your own encryption key lets
customers rotate security keys on the
month if there's uh compliance security
reasons on their end,
uh but more importantly, it also enables
the customer to revoke Microsoft's
access to this key,
uh which immediately makes their data in
the Business Central database on the
sovereign wall by Microsoft. Uh finally,
there's also something customers can do
to um secure their integrations between
Business Central environments and other
services.
For this, we have the Dynamics 365
Business Central service tag that
represents a group of IP addresses from
which traffic uh of a Business Central
environment may come. So, by using the
service tag in your firewall, you make
sure that your integrations don't accept
any traffic from sources that are not
Business Central.
The third functional area for Cloud for
Sovereignty is called Sovereignty
Controls. For that, I'll hand over back
to Christina.
Yes, thank you. Let's dig into some of
the details here.
When you create a Business Central
environment, you select the environment
localization.
And as you know, Business Central runs
on Azure infrastructure.
The localization determines the Azure
geo where your database resides. You can
choose, of course, to create an
environment with any localization,
regardless of where your tenant's home
geo is.
You should think of the infrastructure
in three layers. So, first, the
geography is the legal boundary.
Region is where the service is running,
and the availability zone is about how
Azure is protecting against local
failures.
Let's look at an overview here. So, this
is a snapshot from our documentation, so
you can find this table anywhere.
Here is an example of uh a snapshot of
some of the countries. So, uh you can
get an overview of uh the country and uh
where um that country is uh residing in
a region, an Azure region. So, for
example, here you can see that Andorra,
Albania, and Austria are in the European
Azure geography, whereas Argentina is in
Brazil, and uh Angola is in South
Africa.
So, digging into uh this, it is
important to understand the
differentiation between Azure region and
geography. An Azure region has a
physical location where the actual data
center is, what geographical area it
covers, and then the paired region for
backup and failover. In this table, you
can see how a region is paired with a
backup and failover region.
This will cover automatic backups,
built-in redundancy, and high
availability that protects your data and
keeps it accessible during and after any
disruptive events.
Let's look into an example.
Here is an overview of Europe where the
light blue rectangle is the geo,
the dark blue square is the region, one
in Netherlands and one in Ireland,
and the towers in the dark blue square
are the availability zones. Here you can
see you have your data
in availability zone one,
and there is a copy of it in
availability zone two,
and we automatically create also a
backup in North Europe, Ireland, that
can be used in the event of any major
incidents. This way your data in
Business Central is automatically
protected within the Azure
infrastructure.
Next, let's have a look at the final
functional area of cloud for
sovereignty, the transparency controls.
Transparency controls are there to make
sure that customers have visibility and
a record of who's accessed their data,
who's changed their data, and who's
changed the settings in their
environment.
Um this is made up of several features.
First of all, there is features that
allow customers to audit and monitor
their activity.
Um this happens through preview, uh but
also functionality built into Business
Central environments like change logs
and field monitoring.
Um the second area of transparency
controls here is uh scenarios where
Microsoft engineers need to access your
environment, for example, to to help
mitigate a support request.
Uh, this is managed through through
just-in-time access controls on our
ends, but also the customer can be part
of the approval flow here using customer
lockbox.
The first transparency control feature
here is Purview. Purview is a
Microsoft-wide service that allows
customers to audit activity on their
Business Central services and
environments.
Uh, for Business Central, this means
that any activity executed inside an
environment or in the admin center that
requires admin privileges is auditable,
um, in Purview outside of your Business
Central context.
Um, customers can use this to uh,
respond to security events, run forensic
investigations, and meet their own
compliance requirements.
The final transparency controls that we
offer as part of Cloud for Sovereignty
are for scenarios where Microsoft
engineers need to access a customer's
database.
Um, by default, no Microsoft employee
has any access to a customer data, but
in some specific cases, uh, in response
to a support request, there could be a
need for an engineer to access a
customer database to investigate or
mitigate an issue uh, that's reported as
a support request.
Should an engineer determine that they
need access to a customer database uh,
to mitigate or investigate a support
request,
um, they can request this access
internally using just-in-time access
controls. This means that the engineer
needs to justify why this access is
needed,
um, after which it's reviewed
internally, and if approved, uh, the
access is only authorized for a limited
time, and any engineering activity
within the environment is logged so that
it can be audited later on.
Um, should a customer wish to be part of
this approval flow, we offer a feature
called customer lockbox.
So, with customer lockbox, whenever a
Microsoft engineer determines they need
access to customer data to mitigate or
investigate a support request.
They first get their approvals
internally. Once within Microsoft, we've
determined that this request is
justified and the customer does need
access to investigate or mitigate,
um then this request is escalated to a
customer admin. Meaning that the
customer admin can also uh approve or
reject that request. And only [snorts]
if the customer admin approves, will the
uh Microsoft engineer get temporary
access to this data to uh resolve the
support issue.
Um
that makes up the four functional areas
of uh Business Central Cloud for
sovereignty.
Um this is just a high-level overview.
We have elaborate documentation
including links out to all of the
information you need to actually set up
these features and how to use them on
aka.ms/bcsovereignty.
And that concludes our Business Central
launch edition session on Cloud for
sovereignty. Christina, myself, and
others that work on these features are
eager to hear what you think of these
features.
Uh share your thoughts, feedback, ideas.
Let us know if you have specific
customers that have specific needs that
that's are not delivered by this.
And uh we'll engage with you on on Viva
Engage.
Thank you.